<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natural Language Processing on Daniel Moreira</title>
    <link>https://danielmoreira.github.io/tags/natural-language-processing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Natural Language Processing on Daniel Moreira</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Daniel Moreira, {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://danielmoreira.github.io/tags/natural-language-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sci-Int</title>
      <link>https://danielmoreira.github.io/project/sciint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmoreira.github.io/project/sciint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status:&lt;/strong&gt; Ongoing, &lt;strong&gt;Funded by:&lt;/strong&gt; DARPA&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Advisor:&lt;/strong&gt; Prof. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wjscheirer.com/&#34;&gt;Walter Scheirer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Scientific Integrity (Sci-Int) project is an endeavor funded by the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA), whose goal is to develop solutions to identify misconduct in scientific research through the detection of image tampering in scientific papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working together with the Universities of Purdue, South California (USC), Campinas (Unicamp), and the Politécnico di Milano, our team leads the development of techniques to (1) rule out false positive cases of misidentified misconduct, and to (2) better report and document misconduct practices in retraction notices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accomplish item (1), we plan to perform semantic analyses of the suspect paper cases, in order to identify situations in which duplications or manipulations of content were made with fair scientific purpose (e.g., to visually highlight or to better explain previous results). To do that, we plan to use natural language processing to perform basic automated paper text and image caption interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accomplish item (2), we plan to rely on techniques of Provenance Graph Construction to present better explanations of how problematic images relate to each other, and how they share content across different papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-team&#34;&gt;Research Team&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prof. Walter Scheirer (PI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prof. Anderson Rocha (PI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prof. Kevin Bowyer (PI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prof. Patrick Flynn (PI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel Moreira (Postdoc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aparna Bharati (PhD Student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rosaura Vidal (PhD Student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;João P. Cardenuto (Undergrad Student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
